"I want to have fun with you, Hijiri."
“我想跟小圣快乐地在一起”
"That's all I wanted then.
“这段时间的我总在想这件事
I wonder if these are my blunder years."
这就是人家说的黑历史吗？”
Why are you helping me?
为什么你要帮我？
Going this far.
做到这个程度
You're hurt, I'm doing what any teacher would do.
你受伤了 我只是做身为教师应该做的事
Is that all?
只是因为这样吗？
This isn't good.
这样下去不行
Listen,
听着
I have someone I love.
我有喜欢的人
So…
所以…
I'd like to get something from the store downstairs.
我想去楼下便利店买点什么
Right, you must be hungry. I'll get you a drink.
你肚子饿了吧 想不想也喝点什么？
No, I'll go.
我去吧
Kuroiwa, I'll just drive you back--
黑岩同学 我还是送你回…
I bring gifts.
这是手信
-Thank you. -Sorry for the surprise.
-谢谢你 -抱歉 吓了你一跳
I had the urge to come see you.
我突然很想见你
Hijiri, your phone's ringing.
圣 你手机在响
No, I'm glad to hear that.
哪里 那太好了
Yes, goodbye.
是 再见
The light bulb's out?
灯泡烧掉啦？
You heard me say Kuroiwa, didn't you?
刚才你听到我在喊黑岩吧？
-That was his mother on the phone. -Hmm?
-他妈妈打给我 -嗯？
She managed to reach him.
说她联络到他了
That right? There we go.
是吗？弄好了
It was so surprising.
吓了我一跳
I was driving and I found him after he fell from his bike.
开车时发现他从自行车跌下来了
-He had hurt his leg, and… -Oh!
-然后发现他腿受伤… -哦！
Yes, it's on!
好了 亮了！
Okay.
好
All done.
搞定
Hijiri.
圣
I missed you so much.
我特别想你
Me too.
我也是
So grown up.
这么成熟
He's really handsome too. They look good together.
还这么帅气 他们如此相配
I've got no chance.
我一点机会都没有
Like a moth to a flame.
就像飞蛾扑火般
Akira.
阿晶
-Let me see it. -I can do it myself.
-我来看看 -不用 我自己来
It's fine.
不用了
How could you just leave Sport's Day like that?
运动会怎么可以擅自早退？
And get hurt!
还受了伤
Causing your teachers so much trouble.
总是给老师添麻烦
Hey.
喂
What happened?
发生什么事了？
Leave this here for me.
这个放着就好
How is he?
他怎么了？
No matter how much I ask, he doesn't give me a straight answer.
行不通 不管我怎么问 他就是不肯说实话
He still mad about the letter?
他还在生气信的事吗？
-Don't touch-- -It's from Dad.
-不要碰… -这是爸爸寄来的
Stop! Give that here! You don't need to read it!
不要开！还给我！你不用看！
Maybe.
可能吧
I'm not sure I should be making a big deal of that Internet post about Ms. Suenaga.
我不知道我是否应该为了 那个关于老师的帖子就大惊小怪
You don't want to come off as over involved.
感觉太小题大做了
I guess I'll have to wait and see.
只能继续观察了
-You get any sleep? -Yeah, enough.
-你有睡好吗？ -有 还行
-Sorry I only have one pillow. -It's fine.
-对不起 我只有一个枕头 -没关系
Should we go pick one up? We could drive to IKEA.
还是去买一个呢？ 我们可以开车去宜家
What's this?
这是什么？
Probably the student from last night.
可能是昨天的学生放的
I'll put them inside.
我拿进去放
Great weather.
天气真好
Yeah, I figured.
也是
I don't appreciate this.
我不想这样
So stop.
别再这样子了
She's right.
她是对的
-Good morning.
-早上好
Good morning.
早上好
Hey!
喂！
Good morning Kuroiwa, how's your leg?
早上好 黑岩同学 腿没事了吗？
Good morning.
早上好
Bye.
再见
-We just parted ways. -Hmm?
-我刚跟她分手 -嗯？
What?
什么？
It's a four day study camp.
四天三夜的读书合宿
Apparently, it was started last year and was a big hit.
去年举办之后深受好评
With the parents you mean?
是父母觉得吧？
-My senior said it was hell. -No, it's heaven. Study heaven.
-前辈说是地狱 -不 是天堂 读书天堂
-There's no heaven like that. -Ten hours of studying a day?
-才没那种天堂 -一天十小时？
Participation is voluntary, but half of you already signed up.
虽然是自愿参加 但是班上已经有一半以上的人报名了
-It's like cram school. -No way I'm going.
-根本是备考班 -绝对不去
This isn't for fun. It's written right here.
这不是去玩喔 上面也写了
This year's theme is "Independence and self-control."
今年的主题是“自立克己”
You all set up your own study plans.
自己先主动拟定读书计划
We want you to learn initiative.
希望大家能学会自发性
-Sounds perfect for you, Kokonoe. -Yeah.
-太适合你了 九重 -就是啊
Too perfect.
太完美了
XXXXIWA GAVE HIS HEADBAND TO SUENAGA.
（某岩把头带给了末永）
KOBOSHI JUNIOR HIGH RUMORS
（子星中学情报）
There's another post on Kuroiwa.
又有黑岩的帖子了
XXXXIWA GAVE HIS HEADBAND TO SUENAGA.
（某岩把头带给了末永）
-Headband? -Is this true?
-头带？ -真的吗？
He didn't say when I asked.
问他也不回答
Seems true though.
好像是真的
-You wrote it, didn't you? -What? No.
-是你写的吧 是不是？ -什么？才不是
-Then who? -It was you!
-那会是谁？ -是你！
No, it wasn't me.
不 才不是我
XXXXIWA GAVE HIS HEADBAND TO SUENAGA.
（某岩把头带给了末永）
I'm pissed off.
气死我了
Where's Kuroiwa?
黑岩在哪里？
He just left.
他刚走了
Kuroiwa!
黑岩！
I think you should date me.
你应该跟我交往
I think you should forget about Suenaga and date me.
我觉得你应该要忘掉末永 跟我交往
I'm not sure what you want.
就算你这么说
I'm never going to fall in love with you.
我又不喜欢你
Fine.
没关系
That's okay.
那样也没关系
Say it already!
快给我说！
You jerk, you're gonna pay for that!
你这家伙 我绝对不原谅你！
-How did you start dating? -Huh?
-你们怎么交往的？ -咦？
-She confess her love? -What?
-是她告白的吗？ -什么？
Hey, what are you doing?
喂 你们在干嘛？
Hey!
喂！
-That's cold! -The hell are you doing?
-好冷！ -你干嘛啦？
Ow!
好疼！
Come on, get out.
好了 快点上来
Ms. Suenaga, Kuroiwa got a girlfriend!
老师 黑岩交到女友了！
He's dating Iwasaki!
他跟岩崎开始交往了！
Shut up, Kokonoe, you idiot!
闭嘴 九重 你这个笨蛋！
Congrats, Runachi!
恭喜你啊 瑠奈！
-Stupid Kokonoe! -When did this happen?
-笨蛋九重！ -几时发生的？
-Just drop it! -Tell me now!
-不要问了！ -现在说啦！
What is this?
怎么回事？
Why do I even feel relieved?
我怎么会松了一口气？
I'm his teacher.
我明明是他的老师
Just shut up!
闭嘴啦！
Tell me!
告诉我！
Come on, guys!
好了！
Get out of the pool!
你们俩快上来！
I was like "What?"
那个瞬间觉得“什么？”
Can you change that fast?
这种事马上就能变心吗？
Going from "I love you, Ms. Suenaga" to "I got a girlfriend, so bye!"
从“老师 我喜欢你” 到“我有女友了 再见”
That's a sudden turn.
变得真快啊
I mean, that's fine.
我是无所谓啦
I'm actually relieved because it was going to get me in trouble.
其实我反倒松了口气 因为这样继续下去我会更麻烦
But it does make me question it.
但是会觉得之前那又是怎么样？
Now I feel a little dumbfounded.
感觉有点傻眼
He's a young Millennial. Kids these days are like that.
最近的平成男孩都是这样
They're a bit shallow, but that's what makes them cute.
感觉有点肤浅 可是就是这样才可爱
Women of our generation should be ready.
所以我们这年代的女子 要细心照顾他们才行
But I'm a Millennial.
我是平成出生的
I see, well, here's the border. Gen X over here, Millennials over there.
这样啊 那这里是界线 这边是昭和64年 那边是平成元年
Make sure you don't cross it.
请不要越界
I told you to stay on your side!
马上就给我越界了！不要闹了！
We don't have time for this.
没空陪你玩了
Shotaro really didn't notice?
胜太郎真的没发现吗？
You mean when Kuroiwa came to my room?
你说黑岩在我房间的时候吧？
As I was going to give him a ride.
就在我准备开车送他回去时
-Ding dong, Shotaro appeared. -Plus I was all like "Kuroiwa?"
-门铃响了 胜太郎就来了吗？ -而且我还一边喊“黑岩？”
-Did you just laugh? -Of course not.
-你刚才是不是偷笑？ -才没有
I bet you think this is all stupid and silly.
你一定觉得“这个笨蛋真好笑”吧
Was it that obvious?
我的内心话被听到了吗？
But Shotaro doesn't seem to have noticed.
可是胜太郎好像没发现
He's a special kind of thick.
他还真是极品迟钝啊
But that kind of person makes for the best husbands.
不过结婚对象就是要选这种
Or else life gets really testy.
否则的话 生活在一起会很棘手
Shotaro is piling up all the good qualities.
胜太郎很棒
-Pretended? -Yes.
-假装？ -是啊
I pretended not to hear.
我假装听不见
Your girlfriend said the name of another boy called Kuroiwa?
你女朋友叫了另一个叫黑岩的男生？
My danger dodging ability kicked in.
我的闪避危险机能启动了
I once got bitten by a leech while hiking.
以前我曾在登山途中被山蛭咬了
It's important not to panic.
那种时候绝对不能慌张
Just stay calm and spray some alcohol on it.
保持冷静并拿酒精喷它
It comes right off.
马上就会掉下来了
What?
什么？
It means it's important not to react right away.
就是不要马上反应 这很重要
Besides, that Kuroiwa turned out just to be a student.
结果那个黑岩只是她的学生
Student?
学生？
This one?
是这个吧？
There was such a site?
还有这种网站啊？
It's crazy.
真厉害
So much information.
还有很多其他情报
"Coworker T might have the hots for Hijiri?"
“同事T老师对小圣有意思？”
"Hijiri is on a car date with a man!"
“小圣跟男人去兜风！”
No way!
骗人！
But it's just you.
结果居然是你
Hijiri's so cute.
小圣 真可爱
Ms. Haraguchi.
原口小姐
But they say there's no smoke without a fire.
但俗话说无风不起浪
-Kawai. -Yes?
-川合 -嗯？
There are signs.
都是有迹可循的
Like when you think back, there were a lot of strange things going on.
仔细一想就会发现 感觉很奇怪的预兆与迹象
Is this from experience?
是经验之谈吗？
You could say that.
可以这样说吧
I want a taco party.
我想办塔可饼派对
What? Takoyaki?
什么？章鱼烧？
I want to have a taco party. I'll bring over some tortillas.
塔可饼派对 下次我会烤好薄饼拿过去
There's been another post! "The decisive moment!"
又有新帖子了！ “决定性的瞬间！”
The students love these types of rumors.
学生最爱这类谣言了
Someone is really proactively posting these.
有人很积极在留言煽动喔
Who is it?
到底是谁？
Please don't be offended, but I figure I should ask.
希望你别生气 我得问一下
Have you done anything wrong?
你没有做什么越轨的事吧？
What?
什么？
Have you done anything to warrant these rumors with Kuroiwa?
你有没有做会传出这种谣言的事？
-No, not at all. -I thought as much.
-没有 我什么也没做 -我想也是
Ms. Suenaga is engaged with a fiancé who comes and visits all the time.
末永老师都要嫁人了 未婚夫还会常常来找她
There's no way.
这种事怎么可能？
I'll put in a request to delete it.
我马上提出删除申请
Here's a science test we gave the other day.
这是之前的理科考卷
That's a high score!
好高分喔！
I put in a really hard question at the end.
最后我故意放了一道难题
A very difficult high school entrance exam level one.
高中入学考超难等级
It was about the orbital period of Venus.
是关于金星公转周期的问题
Kuroiwa was the only one who got it right.
只有黑岩同学答对
Kuroiwa.
黑岩同学
DELETE PHOTO
（删除照片）
Good luck. Off you go.
加油喔 慢走
Kuroiwa?
黑岩同学？
Finally, where have you been?
你终于来了 你之前都在干嘛？
That's for the study camp.
咦？这是读书合宿申请书
I'll submit it later.
我等一下交
Have you found a high school of your choice yet?
黑岩同学 你还没找到想去的高中吗？
There'll be a seminar at the camp.
读书合宿也会有高中说明会
There are many science oriented schools as well as tech ones,
有很多数理强校 也有产业技术的
and others that specialize in astronomy or biology.
宇宙或生物相关的专门学校
You fill it out?
填好了吗？
Yeah, I did.
嗯 填好了
I was the one who invited him.
我说想跟他一起去就邀请他了
-I see. -Yeah.
-这样啊 -是
That's great.
太好了
Let's go, we'll be late.
走吧 我们要迟到了
-Bye, Ms. Suenaga. -Good luck.
-老师再见 -加油
Come on, it's biology.
快点 是生物课
-Biology? -Yeah.
-生物课？ -是啊
Let's talk some more about your future next time.
黑岩同学 之后再聊聊未来志愿吧
Really think about high school.
也要仔细想想高中的事
Come on, hurry up!
来啦 快点！
Run!
用跑的！
What?
什么？
-Surprised? -Hijiri.
-惊喜吗？ -圣
That's too big a reaction.
也太大反应了吧
I had some time today, so I decided to come visit you.
今天刚好有时间 就想说来找你
What are you doing here, Hijiri?
你怎么来了 小圣？
-This is, uh… -Were you in the middle of work?
-这是 嗯… -你们在工作吗？
A taco party.
在办塔可饼派对
Oh, an office party?
是公司同事一起办的塔可饼派对？
Just us two.
只有我们两个
Tacos.
是塔可饼
-Want to eat with us? Come in. -Hold on, Ms. Haraguchi.
-要不要一起吃？进来吧 -等一下 原口小姐
-Sorry, you can have your slippers back. -You're confusing her.
-抱歉借了你的拖鞋 还你 -你把她搞糊涂了
Come in.
进来吧
Breakup?
分手？
You know, with her girlfriend.
就是之前那个女友
I mean, she doesn't seem that affected.
不过她也没什么反应
She's like an ice queen.
毕竟她就像是冰雪女王一样
Anyway, maybe she was bored or something, she suddenly said she wanted a taco party.
也不知道她是不是很闷 忽然就说要办塔可饼派对
-Isn't she weird? -Who'd you call an ice queen? Weird?
-真是个怪人 -你说谁是冰雪女王？怪人？
I'm sorry.
对不起
Look at what he has.
你看 川合收集了这些
He wants to go on a honeymoon with you.
他说蜜月旅行想跟你去
Hey, don't show her those!
不要擅自拿出来！
Here.
给
SOUTH AMERICAN TOURS
（南美旅行团）
These are the places I said I wanted to go.
这是我之前说过想去的地方
I wanted to go somewhere off the beaten path with you.
我想和你去点特别的地方
It'd be nice if we could go sometime soon.
希望最近有时间能去
Uruguay.
乌拉圭
Okay, shall we get started?
好 要开始吃了吗？
-No thanks. -Vegetarian?
-不用了 谢谢 -是素食者吗？
-Do you want some? -Thanks.
-要吃吗？ -谢谢
Cheers.
干杯
Huh? We're out already?
呃？已经没了？
Kawai, beer me now.
川合 啤酒给我
Here you go.
给
Me too.
我也要
-You two sure drink a lot. -Can you blame me?
-这两位真会喝啊 -你能怪我吗？
I got transferred to Osaka, working with a bunch of men.
被调到大阪 跟一群男人拼命工作
I give my all to work only to get cheated on.
我拼命工作 结果却被劈腿
She cheated?
她劈腿了？
Yes.
是啊
She's the one who came after me first, saying I was the one and everything.
一开始是对方说喜欢我 我是她的唯一
And after all that, she suddenly flipped a switch or something.
结果一下子就变心了
Like give me a break.
饶了我吧
Kawai, beer run, now!
川合 啤酒 现在就要！
Okay, I'm going.
好 现在就去
See you soon.
回头见
She was younger, wasn't she?
对方比你年轻 是吧？
Yes, so carefree.
对啊 随心所欲
She led you around?
像是被对方玩弄在掌心一样吗？
I'm the adult, after all.
因为我是大人了
I've got my responsibilities, but she doesn't care.
我明明有很多事要做 她却毫不在意
You don't know what they're thinking.
也不知道他在想什么
Yeah, not at all.
没错 完全不知道
They always suddenly come and tell you whatever they want,
总是突然跑过来说了一堆话
then when you think they're gone, you can't tell what they're feeling.
正想说怎么忽然不见了 就已经看不懂他的想法了
What do you think--
你觉得这样…
Is that from experience?
你有这种经验吗？
No.
没有
It must have been hard for you.
不过你真的很辛苦吧
Let's drink tonight!
今晚尽情地喝吧！
I'll drink with you.
我陪你喝
Here.
来
Cheers.
干杯
Boss.
社长
I keep checking, but it's definitely wrong.
不管怎么看都是不对的商品
The wrong product's been delivered!
送来的商品是错的！
Okay, just calm down. In situations like this…
我知道了 先冷静 这种情况 …
You just need to calm down in situations like this.
这种情况要尽可能冷静下来
You're the one who needs to calm down!
社长才是要冷静点啦！
I'll ask an associate if they have any in stock.
我先问同行的店有没有货
If not, I'll have to…
如果没有 我就得…
Sorry, I'll call you back.
对不起 我等一下打给你
Akira, make sure you talk with your teachers during camp
阿晶 合宿时要跟老师讨论
and decide on a high school.
决定好要去哪所高中
The local one is fine.
附近的就行了
What're you talking about?
你在说什么？
You need to aim higher or you won't get into a good college.
如果目标不放高一点 就不能去好大学了
I don't need to go to college.
不上大学也没关系
I see.
原来如此
What'll you do instead?
你不念书要干嘛？
Become a furniture-maker.
可以做家具师傅
Like Dad.
或者像爸爸一样
It's your future, so you need to decide it yourself.
你自己的将来自己决定
You can't blame me for how it turns out.
会变怎么样我可不管
If you're gonna keep hiding Dad from me
还不是你都隐瞒爸爸的事…
then I have nothing to say.
所以我跟你也无话可说
You could at least say goodbye!
至少可以说声再见！
Alright, let's take a group picture!
要拍合照啰！
Say cheese!
笑一个！
Nice!
好！
-Thank you, Ms. Suenaga. -Thank you.
-谢谢 老师 -谢谢
-You seen this? -It's you, right?
-你看了这个吗？ -是你吧？
-Who's writing these? -Who?
-这是谁写的？ -谁啊？
Kokonoe.
九重
Read the room.
识相点
There you go.
好的
That's a good boy.
很好
What you listening to?
你在听什么？
Can I?
我可以听吗？
You listen to this?
你都听这种的啊？
Hold on, my bad!
等一下 对不起！
Don't delete it!
别删掉！
Everyone get ready, we're almost there.
请准备一下 我们快到了
Hurry up.
快点
-Everyone turn in your cell phones! -What?!
-首先把手机交上来！ -什么？
-Me too? -Yes.
-我也要吗？ -要
What about an emergency?
遇到紧急事件呢？
If you need to use it for a real purpose, you can ask your teacher.
有需要用到手机时 请跟班主任提出申请
I want to check my e-mail.
我想看电邮啊
Your e-mail's not going anywhere.
电邮不会跑掉
Don't forget to turn your phone off first.
别忘了先关掉手机电源喔
Once you turn in your phone, you can head to your room.
交出手机的人可以回房间了
Come on, hand them over.
好 交出来
Give it up now.
交出来
Thank you.
谢谢
Basically the same.
基本上是一样的
Okay, what happened in the Asuka period of 663?
那么飞鸟时代663年发生什么？
-Battle of Baekgang. -The Taika Reform.
-白村江之战 -大化革新
Correct. How about 672?
很好 那672年？
-The Jinshin War! -The Taika Reform.
-壬申之乱！ -大化革新
Correct. Then how about 701?
没错 那701年呢？
-The Taiho Code. -Correct.
-大宝律令 -没错
When was the Taika Reform?
大化革新是什么时候？
Did someone say the Taika Reform?
有人在问大化革新是什么时候吗？
Civilizations don't have reformations all the time.
没有革新这么多次
In this case, what does "courage" mean?
这时的“勇气” 指的是什么样的勇气？
Please explain in 30 characters or less. Time starts now.
请在三十字内解释 现在开始
-Uno! -Damn it!
-宇野！ -该死！
-You scared me! -We're coming in!
-吓死我了！ -我们进来了！
I can't believe you came. How'd you sneak past everyone?
-你们竟然能来 -你们怎么偷偷溜过来的？
It was totally easy.
就这样轻松过来啊
-Anyone want some snacks? -Yes.
-要吃零食吗？ -要
If you're not asleep by the time I come back, you're sitting in the hallway.
下次进来还没睡的话 就罚你们去走廊坐
For real?
认真的吗？
Ow!
好疼！
-It's another one! -Really?
-又有了！ -真的？
But we confiscated their phones.
但我们明明都没收了他们的手机
Someone must have hidden theirs.
一定有人偷偷藏起来
Give us a break…
饶了我们吧…
The kids are restless enough as it is.
学生现在都还很躁动
Confess your feelings at a study camp?
要读书合宿居然还告白？
I guess it's better now than it used to be.
不过比起某个时期算是好多了
I mean, not too long ago,
我说 一直到不久之前
they'd all sing about love on the TV, how it was all that mattered.
大家一直在电视嚷着 “恋爱吧 爱就是全部”
Thank you.
谢谢
I mean, love, especially when you're still a child,
说起来恋爱这种事 尤其还是小孩子的时候
is just a way to escape reality and seek out approval.
就是在逃避现实 是一种希望得到别人认同的欲望
The students need to focus on…
学生们应该专注于…
Oh, it's getting late. We should get going.
哎呀 已经那么晚了 我们该回去了
…objectives.
…目标
Objectives, yes.
目标 是的
You have that point covered.
末永老师就很坚定
Totally.
是啊
You already have a fiancé.
有个结婚对象
Mr. Tanabe, it's time you settle down.
田边老师也该认真点了
If only I had a partner to do it with.
就是没有对象
-You know… -Okay then.
-你知道… -好了
I also struggled between choosing work or marriage.
我以前曾经犹豫要选择工作还是结婚
Someone on a matchmaking date once told me we were well matched.
相亲时的对象曾说我们很相配喔
Never mind, I shouldn't.
算了 这些事就别提了
No, we're interested!
我们很想听！
We'd love to hear it.
请务必说给我们听
-Really? -Yes.
-真的吗？ -是啊
It's a long story. You don't mind?
可是说来话长喔 你们不介意吧？
I can't anymore. I didn't get any sleep last night.
我不行了 昨晚不够睡
It was Ms. Shioya's one woman show last night.
昨晚根本是盐谷老师的独唱会
Iwasaki?
岩崎同学？
What's wrong? Are you not feeling well?
怎么了？身体不舒服吗？
No.
不是
What's wrong?
怎么了？
I…
我…
Kuroiwa dumped me.
我被黑岩甩了
Sorry.
抱歉
I just don't have…
我果然…
feelings for you.
不喜欢你
Did something happen?
发生什么事了吗？
You tell me.
老师告诉我吧
What happened between you and Kuroiwa?
你跟黑岩发生了什么事？
Nothing happened.
什么事都没发生啊
There's no way that's true.
骗人的
I watch him more than anyone--
因为我一直注视着黑岩…
I already have someone.
我有对象了
I have someone I care about.
我有喜欢的人
This puts me in a bad position.
被这样说我很困扰
Is he your boyfriend?
他是你男朋友吗？
That's right.
是啊
But it's long distance, isn't it?
但是远距离恋爱 不是吗？
He might fall for someone else when you're apart.
你们不在一起时 他说不定会喜欢上别人
But I trust him.
但是我相信他
Does he trust you back?
他也相信老师吗？
He does.
他也相信我
-Thank you for your time today. -Thank you.
-今天谢谢你们 -谢谢
-Good day. -Goodbye.
-再见
Okay, want to grab some food?
好 要去吃饭吗？
No, I'm good for today.
不 今天就算了
Have a good one.
辛苦了
Bye.
再见
Treat me to dinner.
请我吃饭吧
-What? -I'm really in the mood for meat.
-什么？ -我今天特别想吃肉
The schedule for the India project is going to be brutal.
印度项目的行程会很紧凑啊
-Nonstop business trips. -Shall I go for you instead?
-不停地出差 -要代替你去吗？
-Make sure you cook it well. -Thanks.
-请烤熟再吃 -谢谢
I mean, you're so heavily involved. Isn't it hard?
因为原口小姐全力以赴啊 你不会很辛苦吗？
Not at all.
完全不会啊
I mean, I suddenly find myself with ample free time.
我现在突然觉得很空闲
I can make things go quicker.
我做的话进展比较快
So you pretend.
所以你伪装
You pretend to be strong, an ice queen.
你伪装成坚强女性 冰雪女王
I'm starting to understand who you are.
我越来越了解原口小姐了
I wonder how things would be if I didn't try to act cool and be more myself.
不知道我假如不装成女强人 表现更多自我的话会怎么样呢？
-Here. -It's not ready.
-给 -还没好
Okay.
是
What about you?
你呢？
Huh?
嗯？
You don't ever try to act all cool and mature?
你没试过装成熟耍帅吗？
Something feeling off, being away from Hijiri.
跟小圣分别两地 觉得有点奇怪
When you both can't sense what the other is feeling,
逐渐变得不了解对方的想法
it's best to open up and initiate.
最好是敞开心胸向她坦白
Wait, weren't you a vegetarian?
话说回来 你不是素食主义者吗？
I'm macrobiotic.
我是大自然长寿饮食主义
I eat what I want.
想吃什么就吃什么
I see.
原来如此
Runachi never showed up.
瑠奈没来
It's all your fault.
都是你的错
You're acting scary.
干嘛这么可怕？
Kuroiwa made Runachi cry.
黑岩弄哭瑠奈了
-Why? -He dumped her already.
-为什么？ -他甩了她
Stupid Kuroiwa.
笨蛋黑岩
You suck!
你真差劲！
Watch it.
很危险耶
How about it? Something like this.
怎么样？像这种的
They're all handmade and one-of-a-kind.
全部都是手工打造独一无二
I'll write it down here for you. If you have any issues…
我会写在这里 如果你有什么问题…
What? Boss?
什么？社长？
Are you okay, Boss?
社长 你还好吗？
Boss!
社长！
Ms. Suenaga.
末永老师
Sorry doesn't cut it!
道歉就能了事吗！
-Stop, Kuroiwa! -Kuroiwa, stop!
-住手 黑岩！ -黑岩 住手！
-Kuroiwa!
-黑岩！
What's this commotion!
在闹什么！
Ms. Suenaga!
老师！
Stop!
住手！
What are you doing?
你们在干嘛？
Stop this.
停下来
Kuroiwa, stop!
黑岩 住手！
What is going on here?
到底发生什么事？
What are you doing? What happened?
你在干嘛？发生什么事了？
-It's none of your business! -Of course it is!
-跟老师没关系！ -怎么可能跟我没关系！
You caused a scene.
引起这种骚动
What did you come here to do?
你到底来这里做什么？
Everyone came to study.
大家都是来复习
They're doing the work seriously.
他们很认真在复习
You just decided to ruin things for everyone!
可是你却给大家搞破坏！
If you don't want to study go home.
如果你无心复习就回家吧
I'm disappointed.
我很失望
This is a crucial time for you.
现在对你来说是非常重要的时期
You may think you'll decide your future sometime down the road,
也许你觉得决定未来志愿 离现在还很久
but the high school you choose will have a profound effect.
但选择哪所高中将会决定未来
Your life will change.
你的人生会因此改变
And at such a crucial time,
在如此重要的时刻
all you can do is disappoint everyone around you.
你却只会让周围的人失望
You're throwing away all your talent and abilities.
糟蹋自己的资质和能力
How disappointing.
太令人失望了
Come with me.
跟我来
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
You too, Ms. Suenaga.
末永老师 你也过来
Okay.
好的
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
-Ms. Suenaga, I'll look after him. -Thanks.
-老师 我会陪他 -谢谢
Your mother collapsed.
你妈妈好像倒下了
We just received word that she collapsed at work and was taken to the hospital.
刚才我接到通知 她在工作时倒下被送医了
You should go to her.
你现在马上去陪她
Ms. Suenaga, please arrange his return home.
末永老师 请帮他准备回去的手续
Of course.
是的
Hey.
我说
Can you tell me what happened?
你可以告诉我发生什么事吗？
Why did you attack Ebihara?
为什么要打海老原同学？
The train will be here soon, take it to the last stop.
电车马上就来了 上车之后搭到最后一站
Mr. Jofu from your mother's work should come by to pick you up.
然后 你母亲公司的 上布先生会来接你
Here.
给
Yes?
是
Ms. Suenaga.
末永老师
We just reached the station.
我们刚到车站
I'll return once he's on the train.
他上车后我马上回去
After some questioning,
这边刚问完话
it turned out he made those posts.
他原来就是写下留言的人
What?
什么？
You know, all of those posts relating to you.
就是关于你的那些帖子
Ebihara was the one behind them.
都是海老原同学写的
He was also the one who found your login and password,
也是他捡到你的登录密码
and sent all those e-mails pretending to be you.
假冒老师的电邮也是他发的
He just uploaded images for fun at the beginning.
一开始只是好玩才上传照片
Michiru!
阿满！
-Good morning.
-早上好
When he saw the reaction he got,
后来他看到得到很多回应
he couldn't stop.
他就无法停止
Crap.
该死
WITCHY WOMAN
（魔女）
Ebihara, Ms. Suenaga needs help carrying some things in.
海老原 老师在叫你帮忙搬些东西
Okay, I'm coming.
好的 我来了
Kuroiwa found the tablet and questioned him.
黑岩看到平板电脑后去逼问他
What the hell is this?
这是什么？
"Dirty woman." "Has a fiancé but will do it with anyone."
“下流的女人” “明明有未婚夫却谁都可以的女人”
"Wily." "Witchy woman."
“做作” “魔女”
My bad, but everyone was eating it up.
抱歉 就像你看到的
It became kinda fun, but I promise--
我觉得很好玩 但我答应…
Screw you!
开什么玩笑！
-You hurt Ms. Suenaga! -Kuroiwa!
-竟敢伤害老师！ -黑岩！
Sorry doesn't cut it!
道歉就能了事吗！
Kuroiwa! Let's go!
黑岩！住手！
You hurt Ms. Suenaga, sorry isn't gonna cut it!
竟敢伤害老师 道歉就能了事吗！
Kuroiwa!
黑岩！
What are you doing?
你在干嘛？
So I think we should overlook this incident.
所以这件事我们就不追究了
Okay.
好的
I understand.
我知道了
Goodbye.
再见
Does she have a fever?
她是不是发烧了？
She's usually around 35 degrees.
她平常只是烧到35度左右
She said she gets dizzy with just a little fever.
她说只是一点小发烧就会晕头转向
Your mom?
你母亲吗？
I found a letter.
我找到一封信
From my father.
我爸寄来的
I didn't know about it.
我什么都不知道
And she won't tell me.
她也不告诉我
So before I came to camp,
所以出门的时候
we got in a fight.
我们吵架了
"Take a gander, take a gander."
《急急赶赴一见 急急赶赴一见》
Do you know it? It's an old poem by Mokichi Saito.
你知道吗？ 这是一首是斋藤茂吉作的短歌
He wrote it as a song while he was on a train to see his dying mother.
他搭上火车 回去看望病危的母亲时作了这首短歌
"In Yamagata, my mother is close to death.
“在山形 于母亲命危之际 急赶赴一见”
Make haste so I may catch a glimpse."
“急急赶赴一见 如归箭般快马加鞭”
If you understand how that feels,
如果你能懂得这种心境
then you'll be okay, you and your mom are connected.
那就不用担心 你跟母亲是心意相通的
She's not dying is she?
她不是病危吧？
What?
什么？
No, of course not.
不是 当然不是
Just a little anemia from overwork.
上布先生说
Is what Mr. Jofu said.
是因为过劳引发轻微贫血
Sorry.
对不起
It's a nice song.
是首很好的短歌
What happened
刚才
with Ebihara.
海老原同学的事
You can't go punching people.
你不可以动手打人
No matter the reason.
无论发生什么事
Even if it's for me.
即使是为了我
Mr. Jofu will be waiting at the last stop.
上布先生会在终点站等你
What?
什么？
Huh?
咦？
What will you do during summer break?
暑假你要做什么？
What?
什么？
I'll give supplementary lessons and coach swimming.
我会教补习和游泳
I'll also go to IKEA.
我还要去宜家
-Then I'll go with you. -No.
-那我也一起去 -不行
I see.
是吗？
Excuse me.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
对不起
Over here, Akira.
阿晶 这边
Akira.
阿晶
-How's Mom? -Hello, Ms. Hijiri.
-妈妈怎么了？ -老师 你好
-Does she have a fever? Is she awake? -She's fine.
-她发烧了吗？恢复意识了吗？ -她没事
Ms. Suenaga!
老师！
Thank you!
谢谢！
You finally don't look like death.
脸色终于好多了
Thank goodness.
太好了
Were you worried?
你很担心我吗？
Not really, they already said you'd be fine.
没有啊 他们都说你没事了
I was dreaming.
我作了场梦
Back when we first moved here.
以前刚搬来这里时
You were so worried.
你总是很担心
Yeah, you were worried about robberies.
担心妈妈会不会遇到强盗
And also meteors falling from the sky.
会不会被空中落下的陨石砸中
You said "Because if you leave me,
你说：“妈妈如果离我而去
I'll be all alone."
我就只剩一个人了”
I'm sure
我知道你一定
you were worried.
很担心我吧
I'm sorry.
对不起
Bye, take care.
辛苦了 再见
Great job.
大家都很努力喔
-Bye.
-再见
-Be careful.
-路上小心
She was already released?
她已经出院了吗？
Yes, Kuroiwa's mom is okay.
是啊 黑岩同学的妈妈已经没事了
I'm sure he was worried when he heard she collapsed.
不过听到妈妈倒下 黑岩肯定很担心吧
-So she went with him to the last stop. -What?
-所以她还送他到终点站 -什么？
Ms. Suenaga said she was worried about his behavior,
末永老师说很担心他
so she went with him to the last stop.
所以她送他到终点站
She can be so earnest.
她在这方面真的很用心呢
I hope this doesn't start some more stupid rumors.
希望不会又引起奇怪的谣言
It made me realize I didn't have any plans.
话说我暑假
For summer vacation.
真是毫无计划
He asked me what I'll do.
他问我暑假要干嘛
This would be too far to travel.
这些地方都太远了
So I'm thinking I may go to Osaka.
所以我想干脆去大阪好了
It could be nice living like newlyweds at Shotaro's.
在胜太郎的房间过过新婚夫妻的生活
Kind of like a test run of married life.
就像练习新婚生活 感觉挺不错
So, are you not going with him?
那你最后还是不去吗？
No, I'm not going to IKEA.
不 我才不会去宜家呢
There's no reason for us to go together, and it's to buy Shotaro a pillow.
也没理由一起去 而且我想买的是胜太郎的枕头
I meant a vacation.
我是说旅行
What?
什么？
I'm asking you if you're not going to go on a trip with Shotaro.
我想问的是 你还是不跟胜太郎去旅行吗？
We will, some day. Probably for our honeymoon.
总有一天会去的 应该是蜜月旅行的时候吧
Shotaro recommends a place called Fray Bentos in Uruguay.
胜太郎建议去乌拉圭的弗莱本托斯
Just stop.
别说了
You're lying.
你在说谎
Ever since you met that boy…
自从你遇到那个男孩…
"Nothing would happen with a student."
一直说对方是学生 所以不可能
"Just to treat his wound." "I was worried to leave him alone."
帮他敷药 因为担心所以陪他到终点站
All lies.
全部都是谎言
Lying to yourself.
自欺欺人
Runa!
瑠奈！
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Akira went to the drug store.
阿晶刚去药局
He went to get me medicine.
他去帮我领药
Akira is being preyed on.
阿晶被盯上了
What?
什么？
I'm not sure how much you know,
我不清楚您知道多少
but our teacher Ms. Suenaga constantly looks over at Kuroiwa during class,
但我们班主任末永圣上课时 总是偷偷在看黑岩
totally seducing him, or ignores him to pull away.
一直诱惑他 却又突然故意无视他 引起他的注意
She's leading Akira around, even getting jealous of me.
她刻意玩弄阿晶 连对我也产生敌意
When you were in the hospital, she took the opportunity to be alone with him.
上次阿姨进院的时候明明陪他 去车站就好 却故意一起搭到终点站
I don't know if she's a predator or getting cold feet,
我不知道她到底是淫荡教师 还是不想结婚
but everyone says she's weird.
但大家都在说她很奇怪
I'm worried for Kuroiwa!
我很担心黑岩！
What about Ms. Suenaga?
老师怎么了？
Excuse me.
不好意思
Runa!
瑠奈！
I'll just say this.
我给你个忠告
You can't erase your feelings for someone.
喜欢的心是绝对无法忘记的
It's impossible.
不可能
Your true feelings will be found out. Always.
其实并不喜欢对方的想法 绝对会被发现
No matter how hard you try to hide them, feelings don't lie.
无论怎么隐瞒 人心是不会说谎的
It may not seem like it,
可能看起来不像
but I know that.
但我知道
But he takes in what I teach him,
可是他接受了我教导的东西
and says thank you.
还向我说谢谢
Like even someone like me
让我觉得即使是这样的我
has some value.
也有存在的价值
Before I even realized,
等我发觉时
my eyes
我的目光
would follow him.
也离不开他了
You know, I've noticed lately.
最近确实觉得
Hijiri's been acting different.
圣感觉不太一样
Like there's another guy in the picture.
好像是有别的男人
You felt that?
你察觉到了？
Someone was there in Hijiri's room.
有人在小圣的房间
I was relieved when I found out it was just a student.
我知道对方是个学生松了一口气
But then I started wondering if there was someone else.
可是又开始怀疑是不是有其他人
So I'm just pretending.
所以我假装视而不见
Pretending not to notice.
假装没看到
Why do you always pull away when you talk to me?
为什么跟我说话时总是离这么远？
It's hurtful.
我很受伤
I'm being crazy.
我疯了吗？
Something's wrong with me.
我太不对劲了
He's a student.
他是学生喔
It'll ruin your life.
会毁了你的
I know that.
我知道
Nothing more will happen.
不会再有什么事了
I promise.
绝对不会
Ms. Suenaga.
老师
I need to speak with you.
我有话跟你说
Let's go to the festival together.
一起去烟花大会吧
I want you, Kawai.
我想要你 川合
I don't deserve to be called a teacher.
我没资格被叫老师
I don't care what anyone says.
我不在意别人怎么说
I love you.
我喜欢老师
Subtitle translation by: Zensho Yamamoto
字幕翻译：高文欣